Kumudha Narasimhan

≥ kumudhakn@gmail.com

United Kingdom

kumudhan.github.io/

in in/kumudha-narasimhan

SUMMARY

Technical and people leader with 10 years of domain experience in AI and HPC performance optimization across diverse architectures with multiple research publications. Elevates team performance by engaging with technical experts and guiding contributions toward successful outcomes, while aligning with overall business strategy. Experienced in mentoring, coaching and collaborating with engineers and leaders at all levels of the organization. Creates an inclusive environment where everyone can thrive.

SKILLS

Performance optimization

oneDNN, oneMKL, ONNX Runtime and using cuBLAS, cuDNN, CUTLASS, llama.cpp

Programming Paradigms

SYCL, CUDA, C++, Python

Research projects Managed

EU projects - AERO (open cloud acceleration), SYCLOPS (Al acceleration)

Social

Agile methodologies, process design and audit, mentoring

EXPERIENCE

Jan 2023 – Present Edinburgh, UK

Software Engineering Manager

Codeplay Software (Intel Subsidiary)

- Managed 4 specialized Agile teams working on: optimizing llama.cpp for Intel GPUs, developing a SYCL backend for CUTLASS, creating a hardware portable backend for oneDNN, and optimizing SYCL for CPUs. Defined and maintained roadmaps, tracked deliverables, and ensured timely execution across these teams and 2 EU projects, aligning efforts with broader division priorities.
- Drove goal-setting and progress transparency by coordinating division wide OKR reporting, maintaining company workboards, and implementing change requests based on evolving team needs.
- Provided *people-focused leadership* to 18+ engineers through regular 1:1s, feedback, performance reviews, onboarding support, and handling HR related issues across internal transitions.
- Collaborated across functions (HR, Agile coaches, infrastructure, leadership) to support team health, improve internal processes, enable team learning, and guide organizational initiatives.

Nov 2020 – Dec 2022 Edinburgh, UK

Senior Staff Engineer

Codeplay Software

- *Led SYCL integration efforts* for projects like ONNX Runtime and implemented features in libraries such as portBLAS, portDNN and portFFT to optimize performance on heterogeneous hardware.
- Co-authored and contributed to several peer-reviewed publications (PMAM 2022, TACO 2023, P3HPC 2022) by driving technical content, managing review/rebuttal processes, and presenting results at major conferences and client demos.
- Improved engineering workflows and technical processes by establishing CI pipelines, improving reproducibility, defining merge request review protocols, and supporting ISO audit readiness through systematic best practices.

Sep 2019 – Nov 2020 Edinburgh, UK

Staff Software Engineer

Codeplay Software

- Contributed to adding cuBLAS and cuDNN backends into oneMKL and oneDNN to enable GPU acceleration portability for these libraries. Collaborated with compiler teams to develop SYCL features to enable SYCL as a backend for ONNX Runtime.
- Optimized neural network inference on custom hardware for real-time performance as part of a customer-facing project.
- Published research on deep learning performance optimization in top-tier venues (ICS 2021, P3HPC 2020) - tile size selection model and cross- platform DNN portability.
- Presented SYCL tutorials and major events, including IWOCL 2021 and Intel Dev Summit 2021.

Jul 2018 – Jul 2019 Bengaluru, India

Senior Software Engineer

Samsung Research India

- Analyzed *custom profilers and debuggers* for Samsung Tizen native and web applications, enhancing their functionality based on IoT team requests.
- Investigated and resolved issues reported in the Tizen Studio IDE to improve developer experience.
- Coached colleagues for the professional-level internal competitive coding exam, focusing on data structures and algorithms.

Jun 2012 – Jul 2015 Bengaluru, India

Technology Analyst at Investment Banking Division

Goldman Sachs

- Building and standardizing frameworks in C# .NET and Java for all applications developed within the division with *focus on scalability and performance*.
- Inherited several C# projects and led their sustenance, ongoing development, and enhancements, including re-architecting the resource discovery system, entitlement system, and provisioning system.
- Communicated effectively with internal and business stakeholders, inducted and mentored new joiners, and resolved multiple critical issues within deadlines while managing expectations.

EDUCATION

2018

Masters (by research), High Performance Computing & Compilers

Bangalore, India India

Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore, India (Advisor: Prof. Uday Reddy)

Thesis: Optimizing dense matrix computations with PolyMage

- Optimized geometric multigrid computations using a DSL approach [SC 2017]
- A practical tile size selection model for affine loop nests [ISC 2021]

2012

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science and Engineering

Bangalore, India M S Ramaiah Institute of Technology

Selected Publications

- Towards performance portability of AI graphs using SYCL. [P3HPC@SC 2022]
- A practical tile size selection model for affine loop nests. [ICS 2021]
- Towards Cross-Platform Performance Portability of DNN Models using SYCL. [P3HPC@SC 2020]
- Optimizing geometric multigrid method computation using a DSL approach [SC 2017]

Full list of Publications - https://dblp.org/pid/208/1873.html ☑

List of presentation / talks - https://kumudhan.github.io/#publications ☑